Matthew Egbers

29319 Glenbrook Dr, Farmington Hills, Mi 48331 - 248-752-6993 (C) - matt_egbers@yahoo.com

Summary

Software Developer with 9 years experience adept at application development, testing and optimization. Excels at Java/J2EE application development, including coordinating planning, programming and implementation for core modules. Performed this function in the Automotive, Government, Health Care, Education, Telecommunications and Marketing Research industries.

Key Skills

- Java/J2EE
- Javascript
- Test Driven (JUnit and Mockito)
- Agile Software Methodologies

- Web Services (REST and SOAP)
- Spring Framework
- SQL

Accomplishments

- Built mobile version of a eLearning platform. The application was memory intensive and the challenge was getting it to run in Mobile Safari's 64MB of RAM.
- Maintained several legacy applications. Used TDD and other best practices to increase code coverage, and thus maintainability. This usually meant going from less than 20% to greater than 85% code coverage.
- Co-led a self organized team to create a mobile version of an existing product. The result of this effort was the business seeing value in and funding it as a priority.

Experience

DTE Energy

November 2013 to Current

Senior Software Developer

Detroit, Mi

Worked on the Web Services team. The team is responsible for 12 web services, both REST and SOAP, that are consumed by various front ends.

Cengage Learning

March 2010 to November 2014

Senior Software Developer

Farmington Hills, Mi

Developed and maintained a system for the higher learning market. The platform allows instructors to embed assignments and other content in line of online textbook. The application has rich client interface, and it communicates to a RESTful back end server for data persistence.

Budco

May 2009 to March 2010

Software Developer

Highland Park, Mi

Maintained and improved a customer tracking system. The system is responsible for registering and communicating with customers and then reporting on the results.

University of Michigan Health Systems

August 2008 to March 2009

Software Developer

Ann Arbor, Mi

Member of the Custom Application Team. The team of 8 developers were responsible for the maintenance and enhancements of 15+ Application. The applications were both web based and desktop.

ACN Incorporated

October 2007 to July 2008

Software Engineer

Farmington Hills, Mi

Maintained and improved 2 legacy systems. One was the customer facing application for ordering long distance phone service. The second was used by customers to order VoIP service.

ePrize

May 2006 to October 2007

Software Engineer

Pleasant Ridge, Mi

Developed wizard driven promotion engine. The application allows users to deploy and

administrate semi-custom flash promotions. The actual promotion games were in Flash and communicated with a Java back end. There was also a Java web application for administration and reporting.

Oakland County August 2005 to May 2006

Junior Web Application Developer

Pontiac, Mi

Developed a web based J2EE application for the Oakland County Medical Examiners Office. The system was a replacement for an existing VB application.

General Motors

September 2004 to August 2005

Junior Application Developer

Detroit, Mi

Worked on a team that developed a system for the Standards Team at GM. The application would take employee requests for technology standardization and then track them through the approval process.

Education

University of Vermont Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Burlington, VT

2004